Hi. I'm Sanjana Reddy, a machine learning
嗨，我是Sanjana Reddy，一名在谷歌高级
解决方案实验室的机器学习工程师。
0 engineer at Google's Advanced Solutions Lab.
Welcome to the lab walkthrough for Transformer models and BERT model.
欢迎来到Transformer模型和BERT模型的实验室演示。
In this lab walkthrough, we'll be going
在这个实验室演示中，我们将通过使用预训练的Bert模型进行分类。
through classification using a Pre-Trained Bert model.
You'll find the setup instructions in our GitHub repository.
您可以在我们的GitHub仓库中找到设置说明。
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
In order to work on this notebook, you'll need to log into Google Cloud,
为了在这个Notebook上工作，您需要登录谷歌
云，进入Vertex AI，然后点击Workbench。
go into Vertex AI and click on Workbench.
Make sure that you have a notebook created once a notebook instance
确保在Notebook实例创建后，您已经创建了一个Notebook。
has been created.
Click on Open Jupyter Lab.
点击打开Jupyter Lab。
Once you've followed the instructions in our GitHub repository,
按照我们GitHub仓库中的说明操作后，
导航到使用Bert对文本进行分类。
navigate to classify text with Bert
in this notebook, we're going to learn how to load
在这个Notebook中，我们将学习如何从TensorFlow Hub加载一个预训
练的Bert模型，并使用预训练的Bert模型构建我们自己的分类。
a Pre-Trained Bert model from TensorFlow Hub
and build our own classification using the Pre-Trained Bert model,
we learn how to train a Bert model by fine tuning it
我们将学习如何通过微调来训练Bert模型。
before you get started.
在开始之前，请注意，这个Notebook需要一个
GPU，因为训练确实需要相当长的时间。
Note that this notebook requires a GPU
because the training does take quite a bit of time.
When you open this notebook,
当你打开这个Notebook时，有一个设置说明，以便设置一
个bert_kernel来安装这个Notebook所需的所有库。
there is a setup instruction in order to set up a bert kernel
to install all the required libraries for this notebook.
For this notebook, we're going to be using
对于这个Notebook，我们将使用TensorFlow和TensorFlow Hub
TensorFlow Text，这是为BERT模型预处理输入所必需的。
TensorFlow and TensorFlow Hub TensorFlow Text,
which is required to pre process the input for the BERT model.
You can see that I'm checking if a GPU is attached
你可以看到我在检查是否有GPU连接，我
发现这个Notebook有一个GPU连接。
and I see that I have one GPU attached to this notebook.
In this notebook we're going to train a sentiment
在这个Notebook中，我们将训练一个情感分析模型，
根据评论的文本将电影评论分类为正面或负面，我
们将使用IMDB数据集，你可以从这个URL下载。
analysis model to classify movie reviews as either being positive
or negative based on the text of the review,
we're going to be working with the IMDB data set
that you can download from this URL.
Once we have downloaded
一旦我们下载了数据集，我们可以查看数据以了解其中的内容。
the data set, we can examine the data to see what's in it.
and negative, and we're going to be using 20,000 files
A sample of this dataset shows you the movie review
这个数据集的一个样本向您展示了电影评论和相关标签。
over here and an associated label.
So for the one over here, we see that the label that is associated is negative
所以对于这里的一个，我们看到关联的标
签是负面的，而下面这个是正面的。
and the one below here it's positive.
Once we've examined our dataset and we're happy with that, we're
一旦我们检查了数据集并对其感到满意，我们将从
TensorFlow Hub加载一个预训练的BERT模型。
going to load a Pre-Trained BERT model from TensorFlow Hub.
TensorFlow Hub offers multiple
TensorFlow Hub提供了多种不同大小的BERT模型。
different variations of BERT models in all different sizes.
We're going to use a small BERT for today's notebook.
在今天的Notebook中，我们将使用一个小型BERT。
So this bert model has four different layers.
这个Bert模型有四个不同的层。
It has 512 hidden units, and it has eight attention heads.
它有512个隐藏单元，有8个注意力头。
For every BERT model that we load from TensorFlow Hub,
对于我们从TensorFlow Hub加载的每一个
BERT模型，它都有一个相应的预处理模型。
it is associated with a corresponding pre-processing model.
You can find the corresponding pre-processing model on TensorFlow Hub
您也可以在TensorFlow Hub上找到相应的预处理模型。
as well.
We're going to examine the pre processing model.
我们将研究预处理模型。
So we have we're going to load the pre processing model
我们将加载预处理模型，就像在前面的步骤中
看到的那样，并在这里传递一个示例文本。
we see in the previous step and we pass a sample text over here.
So we just passed.
我们刚刚通过了。
This is an amazing movie and we're going to examine the output.
这是一部很棒的电影，我们将检查输出。
The pre processing model gives us multiple outputs.
预处理模型给我们提供了多个输出。
The first is the input word ID.
第一个是输入单词ID。
The input word ID is the idea of the words
输入单词ID是被分词的句子（Tokenized Sentence）中单词的ID。
in the tokenized sentence.
The pre-processing model also provides
预处理模型还为每个单词提供了掩码（Masking）。
us the masking for each word.
Every sentence is converted into a fixed length input,
每个句子都被转换成固定长度的输入，屏蔽掉无效的词语。
and it masks words that are not valid.
bert model from TensorFlow Hub
in this particular cell block.
这没有什么意义，因为我们还没有训练模型。
It doesn't really make any sense because we've not trained the model.
This is just a random list of numbers at this point.
这只是一个随机的数字列表。
But once you pass the pre process text into this bert model,
但是一旦你把预处理的文本传递给这个Bert
模型，你就会得到一些嵌入（Embedding）。
you get certain embeddings.
So in order to define our classification model,
所以为了定义我们的分类模型，我们从一个输入层开始。
we start with an input layer.
The input layer takes the raw text as input
输入层接收原始文本作为输入，将其传递给处理层进行
预处理，将其转换为Token ID、Bert ID 和 Mask ID。
passes it on to the processing layer for pre-processing
The pre processed words are then passed to the Pre-Trained model.
预处理后的单词然后传递给预训练模型。
There is an argument here called trainable.
这里有一个名为trainable（可训练）的参数。
Trainable here determines if you want to fine tune the Pre-Trained
可训练在这里决定了您是否希望使用您正在
训练的新数据对预训练模型进行微调。
model using the new data that you're training with or not.
In our example, we are setting trainable to true,
在我们的例子中，我们将trainable设置为True，
这意味着我们将更新预训练模型的初始权重。
which means that we're going to update the initial weights
of the Pre-Trained model.
set this to true or false depends on two things
whether you want to update the weights
and second, on the size of your dataset,
if you have a relatively small data set, it is recommended to set this to false
如果您有一个相对较小的数据集，建议将此设
置为False，以免在预训练权重中引入噪声。
so that you're not introducing noise into the pre-trained weights.
Once we have our pre-trained model, we pass it through a dense layer
一旦我们有了预训练模型，我们将其通过
一个密集层，以获得每个类别的概率。
This is what the output from the model is going to look like.
这就是模型输出的样子。
true, is positive or negative.
Since we're working with a binary classification problem,
因为我们正在处理一个二分类问题，所以我们将使用
BinaryCrossentropy作为损失函数，优化的指标将是
BinaryAccuracy，
we're going to use BinaryCrossentropy as our loss function
and the metric to optimize for is going to be BinaryAccuracy
for initializing
通过定义优化器，我们开始初始化我们的训练。
our training by defining the optimizer.
models.
Once we initialize the training,
一旦我们初始化训练，我们可以开始使用model.fit进行训练。
we can start training using model dot fit.
We can pass the train dataset and the validation dataset
我们可以传递训练数据集和验证数据集以及我们想要训练的周期数。
and the number of epochs that we want to train for.
Once the model has trained, let's evaluate the performance of the model.
一旦模型训练完成，让我们评估模型的性能。
So in our case we see that the model achieved an accuracy of 85%,
在我们的例子中，我们看到模型达到了85%的准确率，
考虑到我们只训练了五个周期，这是相当不错的。
which is pretty decent considering we only trained it for five epochs.
You can potentially thwart the accuracy
您可以潜在地阻止准确性和损失随时间变化，以便可视化模型的性能。
and loss over time in order to visualize the model's performance.
0 We see that the training loss is going down
我们看到训练损失正在减少，我们可以稍微改进一下验证损失。
and we could work on our validation loss a little bit.
But for the sake of demonstration, we've only trained it
但是为了演示，我们只训练了五个周期。
for five epochs.
Once you're satisfied with the model that you've trained, you can save the model
一旦你对你训练的模型感到满意，你可以使用model.save
EXPORT_PATH保存模型，将TensorFlow模型保存到本地路径。
using model dot safe model dot save export.
So TensorFlow model to a local path.
So the export path in this line is going to be a part
因此，这行中的EXPORT_PATH将是您Notebook实例中的一部分。
in your notebook instance.
Once you've saved your model, you can load it to get predictions.
保存模型后，您可以加载它以获得预测。
So in this example we have this is such an amazing movie.
在这个例子中，我们有这是一部令人惊叹的电影。
This movie was great.
这部电影很棒。
The movie was okay-ish, the movie was terrible.
电影还可以，电影很糟糕。
And we get predictions
我们根据训练的模型得到每个句子的预测。
for each of these sentences based on the model that we have trained.
If you would
如果您想进一步部署您的模型到 Vertex AI 以获得在线
预测，您可以将本地保存的模型导出到 Vertex AI。
like to take this further and deploy your model on Vertex AI to get online
predictions, you could take the locally saved model and export it to Vertex AI.
in order to do this, you need to check the signature
为了做到这一点，您需要检查模型的签
名，以了解如何将预测传递给模型。
of the model to see how you can pass predictions to the model.
The signature of the model shows you what is the first layer
模型的签名会告诉您哪个是接收输入的第一层。
that is taking input.
So once we have the locally saved model,
所以一旦我们有了本地保存的模型，我们将使用这
些命令将模型推送到 Vertex 的模型注册表。
we are going to push the model to Vertex’s Model Registry
using these commands.
In order to put the model in Vertex’s Model Registry,
要将模型放入Vertex的模型注册表中，您需
要确保拥有一个Google Cloud存储桶。
And these lines over here, let you create a bucket.
这些代码行可以让您创建一个存储桶。
If it doesn't already exist,
如果它还不存在，我们将使用gsutils cp复制本地保存的模型，
we're going to copy the
locally saved model using GS Utils CP
which takes a locally saved model from the export pack
它从EXPORT_PATH中获取本地保存的模型，
并将其放入Google Cloud存储桶中。
and puts it in the Google Cloud storage bucket.
Once the model is in the Google Cloud Storage bucket,
一旦模型在Google Cloud存储桶中，我们将
把它上传到Vertex AI的模型注册表中。
we're going to upload it to Vertex AI's model registry.
We're using the Python SDK in this case.
在这个例子中，我们使用Python SDK。
So we have a platform dot model dot upload, which takes the model
我们有aiplatform.model.upload，它从Google
Cloud存储桶获取模型并将其放入模型注册表中。
from Google Cloud Storage Bucket and puts it in the model registry.
Once the model has been uploaded,
一旦模型上传完毕，我们就可以在Vertex上部署模型并获得在线预测。
we're ready to deploy the model on Vertex
In order to do this, we can use the Python SDK again
为了实现这一点，我们可以再次使用Python SDK，使用已上
传的模型进行部署，这是一个将执行两个操作的函数。
so we can use uploaded model to deploy, which is a function that is going to do
One, it's going to create an end point, and two,
首先，它将创建一个端点（Endpoint），其次
，它将把模型上传到这个特定的端点。
it's going to upload the model to this particular endpoint.
So you can see here that it's creating the endpoint,
如您所见，这里创建了端点，并提供了端点位置。
has been created, the model is deployed to this endpoint.
This step is going to take around 5 to 10 minutes.
这个步骤大约需要5到10分钟。
So just don't worry if it takes too long,
once the model has been deployed to the endpoint, you're ready
一旦模型部署到端点，您就可以从这个端
点获取预测，然后创建一个实例对象。
to get predictions from this endpoint
so you can create an instance object.
So using the signature of the model, we know that
根据模型的签名，我们知道第一个输入层的名称是"text"。
the name of the first input layer is text.
So we're going to pass our review text to this particular key.
我们将把评论文本传递给这个特定的键。
We create this instances
我们创建这个实例对象，它将被传递给endpoint.predict函数。
object that is going to be passed to the endpoint dot predictive function.
And the endpoint our predict function is going to take this instance
endpoint.predict函数将接收这个实例，并给我们预测结果。
So we can see for our first instance, I love the movie and highly recommend it.
我们可以看到，对于我们的第一个实例
，我喜欢这部电影并强烈推荐它。
We have a prediction of 0.99.
我们有一个0.99的预测。
For it was an okay movie in my opinion.
对于这是一部还可以的电影，这是我的看法。
We have 84% and for I hated the movie,
我们有84%，而对于我讨厌这部电影，我们
有2%，这意味着这是一种负面情绪。
we have 2%, which means it's a negative sentiment.
So this is how you can create a classification model from a pre-trained
所以这就是如何从一个预先训练的BERT模型创建一个分
类模型，然后将其部署到Vertex上以获得在线预测。
BERT model and then deploy it on Vertex to get online predictions.